- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
kids:
Aye, aye, Captain!
孩子们：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
kids:
Aye, aye, Captain!
孩子们：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
kids: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
孩子们：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[upbeat rock music]
[欢快的摇滚乐]
♪ ♪
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
[grunts] Mwah.
- Aww.
[咕噜声]哇。
- 哇。
- [laughing]
- [笑]
- Ha ha.
- 哈哈。
- [laughing]
- [笑]
Whoa!
- [quacks]
哇！
- [庸医]
- Aww.
- 哇。
♪ Soon I will get a thrill,
cooking patties on my grill ♪
♪ 很快我就会感到兴奋，
在我的烤架上烤肉饼 ♪
Whee!
哎哟！
[grunts] Whoa!
[咕噜声]哇！
"Krusty Krab closed
on account of urchins"?
“蟹堡王关门了
因为海胆”？
Oh, I must be in a nightmare.
哦，我一定是在做噩梦。
- It's no nightmare, SpongeBob.
- 这不是噩梦，海绵宝宝。
I'm closing the old girl up
for a week
我正在关闭这个老女孩
一周
to get rid
of those prickly pests.
摆脱
那些带刺的害虫。
Plus, I had a coupon
for Urchin B-Gone.
另外，我有一张优惠券
对于 Urchin B-Gone。
- What will become of me?
- 我会变成什么样子？
What am I gonna do
for a whole week?
我要做什么
整整一周？
- Slow your roll, Boy-o.
- 放慢你的滚动速度，男孩。
I've rented you out
to a different establishment
我已经把你租出去了
到另一个机构
for the week,
so is not to disrupt
这周，
所以不要扰乱
me incomin' monies.
我有收入。
- Oh, boy!
- 哦，孩子！
A temporary job sounds
so adventurous.
临时工作听起来
太冒险了。
Is Squidward coming too?
章鱼哥也来了？
- Nope, I got him a job
in the entertainment industry.
- 不，我给他找了一份工作
在娱乐业。
- Whoa.
- 哇哦。
[rowdy circus music]
[horn honking]
[喧闹的马戏音乐]
[喇叭鸣响]
- Still better than working
with SpongeBob.
- 还是比工作好
与海绵宝宝。
- [trumpets]
- [喇叭]
- Where will I be working,
Mr. Krabs?
- 我将在哪里工作，
蟹老板？
- You'll be working right here
at The Salty Spitoon.
- 你将在这里工作
在咸痰盂。
[yelling]
[spits]
[大喊]
[吐口水]
- Aah!
- 啊啊！
- No, thanks.
That place is too tough for me.
- 不，谢谢。
那个地方对我来说太难了。
[screams]
- [snarls, barks]
[尖叫声]
- [咆哮，吠叫]
- You don't have
to be tough to work here.
- 你没有
在这里工作很艰难。
You just gotta look tough.
你只要看起来很坚强就可以了。
- [grunting] There.
- [咕哝] 在那里。
Now you look like a tough guy.
现在你看起来像个硬汉。
- I don't feel tough,
Mr. Krabs.
- 我不觉得艰难，
蟹老板。
- Now when you go in there,
go up to the biggest customer,
- 现在当你进去的时候
走到最大的客户那里，
look him squarely in the eye...
[bell dings]
直视他的眼睛……
[铃声]
And let him know exactly
what you think of him.
并让他确切地知道
你对他的看法。
- No problem, Mr. K.
- 没问题，K先生。
I'm great at looking squarely.
我很擅长直视。
[laughs]
[笑]
- No funny business, Boy-o.
- 没什么好笑的，男孩。
[intense guitar music]
[激烈的吉他音乐]
- Argh!
- Oh!
- 啊啊！
- 哦！
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
♪ ♪
- [laughs]
[cannon blows]
- [笑]
[炮声响起]
♪ ♪
- Whoa!
- 哇！
- [mumbles]
- [咕哝]
- [squeaks]
- Aah!
- [吱吱声]
- 啊啊！
[growls]
[咆哮]
- Huh? [growls]
- 啊？ [咆哮]
- Grr, I'm gonna tell you
exactly what I think of you.
- 呃，我要告诉你
这正是我对你的看法。
You have got the most beautiful
baby blue eyes.
你已经拥有了最美的
淡蓝色的眼睛。
- Aw, thanks.
- 哦，谢谢。
I got 'em from me mother.
我从我妈妈那里得到的。
- Blue eyes?
Everybody knows my green eyes
- 蓝眼睛？
每个人都知道我的绿眼睛
are the most beautiful.
是最美丽的。
- Oh, yeah?
- 哦，是吗？
- Yeah!
- 是的！
[both roaring]
[双方咆哮]
- Aah!
- 啊啊！
- Hey. Yai.
- 嘿。呀。
- [whistles]
- You must be SpongeBob.
- [口哨]
- 你一定是海绵宝宝。
Welcome to The Salty Spitoon.
[spits]
欢迎来到咸痰盂。
[吐口水]
I'm the owner of this joint.
我是这家联合店的老板。
That means youse works
for me now!
这意味着你可以工作
现在对我来说！
- My new boss.
- 我的新老板。
So nice to meet--
很高兴认识——
[groans]
[呻吟]
[heavy rock music]
[重摇滚]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- Here's the grill.
- 这是烤架。
- Wha--aah. [blubbers]
- Here's the spatoola.
- 哇——啊。 [哭声]
- 这是抹刀。
Now make with the grub.
- Aah.
现在用 grub 来制作。
- 啊啊。
- Um, just out of curiosity,
- 嗯，只是出于好奇，
uh, what happened
to your last fry cook?
呃，发生了什么事
到你最后的炒菜厨师吗？
- That's our employee
of the month wall.
- 那是我们的员工
月墙。
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
- Your photo is gonna be next
if you don't get to work!
- 下一张就是你的照片
如果你不去上班！
[smash]
- [winces]
[粉碎]
- [畏缩]
[flames roaring]
[火焰咆哮]
Don't worry, SpongeBob.
别担心，海绵宝宝。
It'll be just like working
at the Krusty Krab.
就会像工作一样
在蟹堡王。
- ♪ La la la la la ♪
- ♪ 啦啦啦啦 ♪
- Keep those patties comin',
pal.
- 让那些馅饼来吧，
朋友。
I love you.
我爱你。
- Gimme a brick covered
in nails
- 给我一块砖盖上
在指甲里
with extra motor oil!
加上额外的机油！
[bell dings]
[铃声]
Huh? What is this garbage?
啊？这是什么垃圾？
I asked for a brick covered
with nails.
我要求盖一块砖
用指甲。
- Oh, I thought
that was just diner lingo.
- 哦，我以为
那只是餐馆行话。
Sorry.
[grunting]
对不起。
[咕噜声]
Brick covered with nails,
extra motor oil.
砖头布满了钉子，
额外的机油。
Salty Spitoon style.
咸痰盂风格。
[spits]
- Hmm.
[吐口水]
- 嗯。
Now that's a tough sandwich.
现在这是一个很难吃的三明治。
[everyone grunting, gasping]
[每个人都咕哝着，喘着粗气]
- Oh.
- 哦。
- Ooh, the brick is so tender,
and the nails are roasted.
- 哦，砖块太嫩了，
指甲被烤了。
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
- Whoo-hoo!
- Got some more orders for you,
- 呼呼！
- 还有一些订单要给你，
SpongeBob.
海绵宝宝。
- 72 bricks covered
in motor oil coming right up.
- 覆盖 72 块砖块
机油马上就出来了。
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[cheering]
[欢呼]
[all gasp]
- Whaddaya know?
[全都喘气]
- 你知道什么？
Whaddaya say, gang?
帮派，说什么？
- It's Puff the Tuff!
- [gasps]
- 这是凝灰岩泡芙！
- [喘气]
[stuttering] Puff the Tuff?
[结巴] 凝灰岩？
[straining]
- [grunts]
[紧张]
- [咕哝]
[laughs]
[笑]
[inhales]
[吸气]
[all groan]
[全都呻吟]
- Gimme a tall glass
of broken glass
- 给我一个高脚杯
碎玻璃的
in a dirty glass.
在脏玻璃杯中。
[glass shatters]
[玻璃碎裂]
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
[chomp]
[咀嚼]
- [laughing]
- [笑]
- That laugh. No!
- 那笑声。不！
It can't be him.
不可能是他。
- Who ordered the bomb-becue?
- 谁下令制造炸弹？
[laughs]
[笑]
- SpongeBob!
- [gasps]
- 海绵宝宝！
- [喘气]
- [groans] Aah!
- [呻吟]啊啊！
[all gasp]
[全都喘气]
- Was that Mrs. Puff?
- 那是帕夫夫人吗？
- Wait a second.
- 等一下。
Why is Puff the Tuff afraid
of you?
凝灰岩帕夫为什么害怕
你的？
- Oh, she probably
didn't recognize me
- 哦，她可能
没认出我
now that I'm a tough guy.
现在我是一个硬汉了。
[horn honks]
Oh, my shoelace is untied.
[喇叭鸣响]
哦，我的鞋带松了。
Safety first.
[boom]
安全第一。
[繁荣]
- Aah!
- That new little cook
- 啊啊！
- 那个新来的小厨师
seems pretty tough.
看起来相当艰难。
- Oh, yeah?
Let's see how tough he is.
- 哦，是吗？
让我们看看他有多坚强。
Let the trials
of toughness begin!
让考验
韧性开始！
Mechanical Sea-bull.
机械海牛。
- Whoa! Whoa! Aah!
- 哇！哇！啊啊！
- Aw, poor thing.
- 噢，可怜的东西。
You're probably tired of people
riding you all the time.
你可能厌倦了人们
一直骑着你。
Take a break and ride me.
休息一下，骑我吧。
- [snorts]
- [laughs]
- [哼哼]
- [笑]
Whee!
[smash]
哎哟！
[粉碎]
Oops.
哎呀。
- Whoo-hoo. Whoo-hoo.
- 呼呼。呼呼。
- Punching bag!
- 出气筒！
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- [growling]
- [咆哮]
Whoa.
哇哦。
[air squeaking]
[空气吱吱声]
- Nice punch, SpongeBob.
- 海绵宝宝，一拳打得好。
- Body hair strength!
- 体毛强度！
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[laughs]
[笑]
- Uh.
- 呃。
Oh.
哦。
I'll just use my abrasive side.
我只用我的磨料面。
[laughs]
[笑]
- [gasps] Aww.
- [喘气] 哇。
- I declare the toughest guy
at The Salty Spitoon...
- 我宣布最强硬汉
在咸痰盂...
[spits]
Is SpongeBob SquarePants.
[吐口水]
是海绵宝宝。
[cheers and applause]
[欢呼和掌声]
[chain clangs]
[链条叮当作响]
Whoo!
呼！
- As our tough guy leader,
- 作为我们的硬汉领袖，
you have the power
to do whatever you want.
你有权力
做任何你想做的事。
- Well, in that case,
I've got a few wild ideas
- 那么，在这种情况下，
我有一些疯狂的想法
for this place.
对于这个地方。
[all quacking]
[都嘎嘎叫]
[motor roars]
[马达轰鸣声]
[upbeat rock music]
[欢快的摇滚乐]
[motor revs]
[电机转速]
[horn honks]
- Aah!
[喇叭鸣响]
- 啊啊！
♪ ♪
[tires screeching]
[轮胎的尖叫声]
- All right, guys.
- 好吧，伙计们。
Prepare to rumble
in the toughest place
准备隆隆作响
在最艰难的地方
in Bikini Bottom.
在比基尼底部。
[cheering]
[欢呼]
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
Huh? [growls]
啊？ [咆哮]
[light music]
[轻音乐]
♪ ♪
Yeah, no, no, no, no.
This is the right place.
是的，不，不，不，不。
这是正确的地方。
What's going on in here?
这里发生了什么事？
I demand to speak
to whoever's in charge.
我要求发言
给负责的人。
[patrons quietly conversing]
[顾客小声交谈]
[old Western music playing]
[古老的西洋音乐演奏]
- Welcome, stranger.
- 欢迎，陌生人。
- Oh. [chuckles]
- 哦。 [笑声]
Why is the cheese talking
to me?
奶酪为什么会说话
对我来说？
- You asked to speak
with the tough leader?
- 你要求发言
与强硬的领导者？
- No, no, really, who let
this guy in here?
- 不，不，真的，谁让
这家伙在这儿吗？
- I see you're admiring
the new décor.
- 我看你很欣赏
新的装饰。
- Tell him how it is, lad.
- 告诉他是怎么回事，小伙子。
- I'll do him one better.
- 我会让他做得更好。
♪ Oh ♪
♪ 噢 ♪
all: ♪ Oh ♪
全体：♪哦♪
- Hey, what's happening?
- 嘿，发生什么事了？
♪ Come one and come all
to The Softy Spitoon ♪
到软痰盂♪
all: ♪ Softy Spitoon ♪
全部： ♪ 软痰盂 ♪
- ♪ Where all of our cupcakes
come with a balloon ♪
- ♪ 我们所有的纸杯蛋糕都在那里
带着气球来吧♪
all: ♪ Softy Spitoon ♪
全部： ♪ 软痰盂 ♪
- If you like head kisses
and cuddly hugs ♪
- 如果你喜欢吻头
和可爱的拥抱♪
all: ♪ Softy Spitoon ♪
全部： ♪ 软痰盂 ♪
- ♪ And raise up your milk
with "I heart Mom" mugs ♪
- ♪ 并提高你的牛奶
带着“我心妈妈”马克杯♪
all: ♪ Softy Spitoon ♪
- ♪ Ready? ♪
全部： ♪ 软痰盂 ♪
- ♪ 准备好了吗？ ♪
all: ♪ Softy ♪
- Enough!
全部：♪ 软软的 ♪
- 够了！
You're acting like a bunch
of weenies.
你们表现得像一群人
的小威尼。
- Weenies?
- 维尼？
We have those,
and they are to die for.
我们有那些，
他们是值得为之而死的。
A dab of freshly pickled
relish, perhaps?
一点新鲜腌制的
也许喜欢？
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
- [cries]
- Hey!
- [哭声]
- 嘿！
There ain't no cryin'
in The Softy--
没有哭泣
在《软软》中——
I mean The Salty Spitoon.
我指的是咸痰盂。
- Well, there is now,
buttercup.
- 嗯，现在有，
毛茛。
And if you don't like it,
you can hike it.
如果你不喜欢它，
你可以徒步旅行。
- Oh, yeah?
- 哦，是吗？
- Yeah.
- [snaps]
- 是的。
- [快照]
[everyone yelling]
[大家大喊]
- Well, let's see
how SpongeBob is doing.
- 好吧，让我们看看
海绵宝宝现在怎么样了。
This oughta be good.
[glass shatters]
这个应该不错吧
[玻璃碎裂]
[gasps]
[喘气]
- Krabs,
what are you doin' here?
- 螃蟹，
你在这里做什么？
The week ain't up yet.
这周还没到呢
- SpongeBob isn't giving you
a problem?
- 海绵宝宝不会给你
有问题吗？
- Problem?
- 问题？
Nah, he's the belle
of the ball.
不，他是美女
球的。
- [chomps] Ah.
[groans]
- [咀嚼]啊。
[呻吟]
- In fact,
the customers like him so much,
- 事实上，
顾客非常喜欢他，
I'm gonna keep him
on permanently.
我要留住他
永久开启。
- You can't do that.
- 你不能那样做。
He's coming back
with me right now.
他回来了
现在就和我在一起。
- Oh, yeah?
- 哦，是吗？
- Yeah.
- 是的。
[gasps]
[both grunting]
[喘气]
[两人都咕哝着]
- I better take you home,
Mr. Krabs.
- 我最好带你回家
蟹老板。
This place is much too tough
for you.
这个地方太难了
为了你。
You might get hurt, see?
你可能会受伤，明白吗？
- Whoa.
- Ha.
- 哇哦。
- 哈。
- Fare thee well,
you old Softy Spitoon.
- 再见，
你这个老软痰盂。
We'll always have...
[spits]
我们永远都会有...
[吐口水]
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
Huh? Hey, everybody.
啊？嘿，大家。
That guy is kidnapping
our leader.
那家伙正在绑架
我们的领袖。
[all grunting]
[全都咕哝]
- ♪ Softy Spitoon ♪
- ♪ 软痰盂 ♪
♪ Softy Spitoon ♪
♪ 软痰盂 ♪
♪ Softy ♪
♪ 柔软 ♪
♪ Spitoon ♪
♪ 痰盂 ♪
[laughs]
[笑]